# Qiaoyi Liu (Joyce)

# Full-stack Software Engineer

t: 650-772-2987 e: qyliu10@gmail.com Cupertino, CA 95014 <u>Linkedin</u> <u>GitHub</u> <u>Portfolio</u>

### **Skills**

Python, Javascript, React, Redux, Node.js, Flask, Express, Restful API, PostgreSQL, Sequelize, SQLAlchemy, AWS, HTML, CSS, Pug, Github, Git, Docker, Heroku, Playwright

# **Projects**

#### Klickr - an image-sharing and social networking platform inspired by Flickr.

live | github

(Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, AWS, HTML, CSS, Docker, Heroku)

- Worked independently on creating 4 backend API routes, leveraging 18 react components, and utilizing vanilla css to build a responsive and dynamic web page.
- Used React frontend with Flask backend to update the PostgreSQL database and Redux store for instant creating, adding, updating, removing albums, images, comments and likes.
- Created custom modal using React component architecture allowing for efficient development of new forms.
- Utilized AWS S3 to implement user image uploads reducing server load and improving user experience.

# NotesOn - a notes-taking app, inspired by Evernote, where users can organize notes in a simple way. <u>live</u> github (Express, React, Redux, JavaScript, Sequelize, Node JS, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Heroku)

- Worked independently on developing 3 API routes and various frontend react components for a logged-in user to create, read, edit, delete and search for their notes and notebooks.
- Configured Node backend with PostgreSQL, using Sequelize ORM for validations and database queries.
- Integrated react-quill library to create rich-text editor where users can edit and format notes easily.
- Implemented custom searching to facilitate notes searches throughout the site.

## Wecord - a discord clone app, which allows users to hang out with friends and communities.

(Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Docker, WebSocket, Heroku)

- Collaborated with 3 other engineers to develop a full-stack application with 5 core features within a week.
- Designed and built a backend database and 6 RESTful API routes by utilizing Python, Flask, and SQLAlchemy.
- Combined SocketIO to implement live chat functions for better user experience.

#### **Experience**

Business Analyst | 2018 - 2020

Vivolight Medical Device & Technology Co Ltd

• **Problem-solving skills**: analyzed large data sets to identify effective ways of boosting organizational and marketing efficiency and enhanced cooperation with different parties.

Business Consultant | 2016 - 2018

Chong Seng Consultants Pte Ltd

• **Project management skills**: supported corporate project management of large scale human resource solutions through cross-functional business collaboration.

Account manager | 2015 - 2016

China Industrial Bank

• **Credit Analysis**: performed in-depth credit analysis of corporate clients, assessed credit risks and issued risk opinions on a regular basis for senior management decisions.

### **Education**

**App Academy** | Full Stack Web Development Training, US | Sep 2022

Immersive software development course with over 1000 hours of class work focusing on full stack web development. **University of Sheffield** | Master of Science | Sheffield, United Kingdom | Jan 2015

Major in International Business and obtained Sheffield Graduate Award in 2015.